<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.4.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://merylye.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><link href="https://merylye.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en"/><updated>2025-08-20T03:10:55+00:00</updated><id>https://merylye.github.io/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Meryl Ye</title><subtitle>MY Personal Website. </subtitle><entry><title type="html">Reflection on PhD Year 1</title><link href="https://merylye.github.io/blog/2025/blog6/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Reflection on PhD Year 1"/><published>2025-08-19T14:14:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-08-19T14:14:00+00:00</updated><id>https://merylye.github.io/blog/2025/blog6</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://merylye.github.io/blog/2025/blog6/"><![CDATA[<p>My minimum requirement for my blog (i.e. Diary of a PhD) is that at the end of each year, I write a post summing up how it went. I started drafting this post early in the summer, but never got around to finishing it. They say that summer is the time to actually do research since I’m not being distracted by useless things like coursework (-_-). I took full advantage of the extra time: I was involved in 4-ish research projects and mentored two undergraduates. It was enjoyable but quite busy. I think this might be my most productive summer yet.</p> <p>Now that classes are starting next week, it’s the official end of PhD year 1. So now I’m hunkering down and finishing this post.</p> <p>I’m going to format this reflection as a list of advice/habits/insight that might be helpful to young researchers. Please note that I <em>just</em> finished my first year, so it is very possible that any or all of this is misguided or flat out wrong. Take my words with a grain of salt, or several spoonfuls of salt.</p> <ol> <li><strong>Talk to someone new every week.</strong> Especially early in your PhD, when you’re still trying to figure out your research interests, it is incredibly helpful to pick the brains of older students and professors. As soon as I arrived on campus, I scheduled a bunch of meetings to chat about grad school, research, life at CMU, etc. A portion of the people I met were via snowball sample–one conversation would lead me to connect with several new people. Another portion were connected via cold email–I just reached out to people whose work I admired and asked to chat about mutual interests. This way, I was able to learn about lots of topics quickly as well as get insider information about academic/department lore.</li> <li><strong>Get used to being awkward.</strong> Though my actions of cold emailing and reaching out to strangers make me appear quite extroverted, I have pretty bad social anxiety. I had so many meetings where I felt stupid or awkward. But it’s gotten easier over time. I’ve come to learn that socializing is an important part of academia. Whether for networking or brainstorming new ideas, learning how to talk to others and communicating well is extremely important. And the best way to do this is through practice.</li> <li><strong>Disentangle your identity from your work.</strong> Coming straight out of undergrad, my identity is deeply tied to how good of a student I am. There is quite a bit of <a href="https://sauvik-das.medium.com/the-emotional-labor-of-your-ph-d-84e24846daff">emotional labor</a> that goes into research. To minimize the emotional toll, it’s important to recognize that when you receive negative feedback, they are critiquing the work, not you. As someone who often takes things personally, I’m still trying to improve on this skill. One time I asked my advisor, “Am I incompetent?”. He responded, “No, this is just hard.” Sure, there is always room for you to improve as a researcher, but don’t view your shortcomings as deficiencies. Look at them as opportunities to grow, and recognize that everyone’s been there at one point. There’s nothing wrong with you.</li> <li><strong>Everyone is working at their own pace.</strong> Another flaw of mine–I compare myself to others all the time. But in a PhD program, you really can’t compare yourself to your peers. The main goal of a PhD is to develop an original stream of research, so of course it’s going to move at different speeds for everybody. The rate at which you’re finishing projects or publishing papers can be dependent on your field, the resources to which you have access, your advisor, alongside a multitude of other factors.</li> <li><strong>Keep a research journal.</strong> Mine is a Google Doc where I jot down what I did that day, whom I talked to, cool papers I found, etc. <a href="https://hci.stanford.edu/msb/gettingstarted/">Michael Bernstein</a> says to spend 20 minutes a day brainstorming, so my research journal is usually where I dump my ideas. <a href="https://www.danah.org/aca-advice/GradSchoolAdvice.html">danah boyd</a> says to write down your research questions once a week, so I do this in my research journal as well. The intention of both advice is to record your thoughts regularly so you eventually see emergent patterns that (hopefully) lead to bigger ideas.</li> <li><strong>Read a lot, but not too much.</strong> For a few months, I received daily emails from arxiv and Google Scholar to keep up to date on all the new papers from my favorite researchers. I also checked Twitter and Bluesky every day to read new paper threads. I got overwhelmed real fast. To mitigate information overload, I now only check for new papers at the beginning of the week (usually on Monday). After skimming a handful of abstracts or threads, I save the ones I found most relevant to Zotero and read the full papers in my downtime. This way, I’m intaking new information on a regular basis but not to the point of driving myself crazy.</li> </ol> <p>Well, I think I’m satisfied with what I’ve written, so I’ll stop here.</p> <p>I kept my reflection/advice mainly research-centric, but I wanted to note that my most favorite part of this year is the people I’ve met. I am so incredibly satisfied with the friends and community I have made in Pittsburgh. I’ve enjoyed many deep, genuine conversations and partaken in much laughter. As difficult and tiring work can sometimes get, I can’t help but smile when I realize how much friendship and support I have acquired over the past year. From friends in my cohort to mentors who are my grandparents’ age, the diversity in thought and perspective I’m able to engage with is wonderful. I feel like I’ve really grown as a scholar and as a person, and I’m excited for more to come.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="reflections"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[My minimum requirement for my blog (i.e. Diary of a PhD) is that at the end of each year, I write a post summing up how it went. I started drafting this post early in the summer, but never got around to finishing it. They say that summer is the time to actually do research since I’m not being distracted by useless things like coursework (-_-). I took full advantage of the extra time: I was involved in 4-ish research projects and mentored two undergraduates. It was enjoyable but quite busy. I think this might be my most productive summer yet.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Protecting a blog and tradeoffs of self-disclosure</title><link href="https://merylye.github.io/blog/2025/blog5/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Protecting a blog and tradeoffs of self-disclosure"/><published>2025-05-25T14:14:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-05-25T14:14:00+00:00</updated><id>https://merylye.github.io/blog/2025/blog5</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://merylye.github.io/blog/2025/blog5/"><![CDATA[<p>I started writing this “blog” as a way to record my experiences during my PhD, perhaps in case one day, if I want to write my own <em>PhD Grind</em>, I’ll already have some material to refer back to. Now, why don’t I just do this via a personal diary/journal? I’m not sure. I’ve never been really good at keeping a journal. I have one “diary” that I’ve kept since fourth or fifth grade, and let’s just say…there are still empty pages in it. The entries have gone from daily to weekly to…annually lol.</p> <p>What makes a blog more appealing to me than a diary–its potential to have an audience greater than one and to have an impact on someone beyond myself. This past year, I have found great comfort in reading about the experiences of previous PhD students who are now professors and/or senior academics. So if I can contribute to that pool of material that provides comfort to a struggling student, even if it’s just one, I am happy to do that. Also, I don’t mind sharing my thoughts and stories to people who would like to read them.</p> <p>Now, given my recent research interests (keywords: self-disclosure, context collapse, networked privacy), I should be cautious about maintaining a publicly accessible blog that could be seen by an inappropriate, unforeseen audience. I am aware that someone for whom this blog was not intended—such as the department head, a future employer, or my high school archenemy—could potentially read it. So my strategy for avoiding repercussions is twofold: (1) minimizing blog accessibility/exposure and (2) curbing my level of self-disclosure in posts.</p> <p>This website is maintained on a public domain, so it is technically accessible to everyone, everywhere, all at once. But I have purposely chosen to maintain it on my personal website rather than a blogging platform to minimize its exposure to a broader audience. Also, rather than have “blog” as a tab on my website’s main menu, it’s nested within a dropdown menu of “more”. So to find this blog, you would have to be really, really interested in me and my scattered thoughts. So much to the point that you have creeped into the crevices of my personal website. This is my way of filtering out an irrelevant, uninterested audience. There is one loophole–sometimes I might link a blog post in my Facebook or Instagram to promote its visibility among my personal social network, in which case, that particular post could receive a click by someone of only mild interest. I don’t do this for all of my posts, only those include writing that I think my followers (who are mainly friends and family) would find worth reading (i.e. life updates, recaps).</p> <p>But, of course, this is the internet, so I should anticipate the possibility of my blog being read by the wrong audience. I have a maximum level of self-disclosure that I am comfortable with exhibiting in my writing. While I am displaying vulnerability when I disclose emotions (both negative and positive) that I experience, I am mindful to not overshare personal details about my life. There is definitely a tradeoff between reaping benefits of self-disclosure and mitigating privacy risks.</p> <p>Am I overthinking this? Maybe. A few months ago, a passionate post-doc whom I met at a conference said to me: “research is me-search”. I am intensely me-searching. But I guess that’s what makes my work fun.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="reflections"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I started writing this “blog” as a way to record my experiences during my PhD, perhaps in case one day, if I want to write my own PhD Grind, I’ll already have some material to refer back to. Now, why don’t I just do this via a personal diary/journal? I’m not sure. I’ve never been really good at keeping a journal. I have one “diary” that I’ve kept since fourth or fifth grade, and let’s just say…there are still empty pages in it. The entries have gone from daily to weekly to…annually lol.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Excited for summer</title><link href="https://merylye.github.io/blog/2025/blog4/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Excited for summer"/><published>2025-05-02T14:14:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-05-02T14:14:00+00:00</updated><id>https://merylye.github.io/blog/2025/blog4</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://merylye.github.io/blog/2025/blog4/"><![CDATA[<p>With summer approaching, it feels like a chance for new beginnings and new projects, which makes me excited.</p> <p>danah boyd was a visiting speaker this week. I was fortunate enough to be invited to a dinner with her and to also have a brief 1:1 meeting. She’s such a rare-find of a human. She’s brilliant, of course, but her humanness and warmth also makes her so approachable–unlike most academics. She’s siren-like, in a non-people-eating kind of way: you can’t help but just sit and listen to her talk. Her words are deeply thought-provoking and her ability to “look at things sideways” is truly amazing. But on the other hand, she’s also a deeply intent listener. Maybe it’s because of her experience with interviewing young people, but you really feel like she cares about what you have to say, and it elicits you to speak vulnerably and honestly.</p> <p>During and after her visit, I feel like my head is in the clouds, dreaming and brainstorming about the ways I see the world and what I can do with my research to make it better.</p> <p>It’s truly such a privilege to be a PhD student. I’m literally being paid to learn and to do research. I’ve said it time and time again: my stress comes from within, and it’s driven by a want and an impatience to achieve tangible goals. But as these past few days have reminded me, <em>my heart is in the work, not the degree</em>. I really love engaging with academics. Whether it’s with my peers or with older researchers, it’s such a joy to engage in these long conversations that meander from one topic to another that come out of pure interest and curiosity.</p> <p>So no, I won’t be in a rush to graduate. There’s plenty of work to do here, and I will be patient. Because the process–the journey–of research is so worth it.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="thoughts"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[With summer approaching, it feels like a chance for new beginnings and new projects, which makes me excited.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Adulting</title><link href="https://merylye.github.io/blog/2025/blog3/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Adulting"/><published>2025-03-21T14:14:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-03-21T14:14:00+00:00</updated><id>https://merylye.github.io/blog/2025/blog3</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://merylye.github.io/blog/2025/blog3/"><![CDATA[<p>I’ve been a little stressed about school. I keep assuming that most of my overwhelm is coming from school and my lack of progress. But I’ve realized that this year has had a lot of changes. I’m not just navigating grad school. I’m navigating how to be an adult. I previously lived in a dorm for college, where I had access to a dining hall. And all I had to clean was a small room with a bed and desk. And do laundry. Now, I have to regularly cook and clean for myself, buy groceries, and do laundry. So not only am I navigating grad school. I’m navigating becoming an adult. I know my peers are doing this as well, but I think it’s still impressive for me.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="thoughts"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I’ve been a little stressed about school. I keep assuming that most of my overwhelm is coming from school and my lack of progress. But I’ve realized that this year has had a lot of changes. I’m not just navigating grad school. I’m navigating how to be an adult. I previously lived in a dorm for college, where I had access to a dining hall. And all I had to clean was a small room with a bed and desk. And do laundry. Now, I have to regularly cook and clean for myself, buy groceries, and do laundry. So not only am I navigating grad school. I’m navigating becoming an adult. I know my peers are doing this as well, but I think it’s still impressive for me.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Losing steam</title><link href="https://merylye.github.io/blog/2025/blog2/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Losing steam"/><published>2025-03-10T14:14:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-03-10T14:14:00+00:00</updated><id>https://merylye.github.io/blog/2025/blog2</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://merylye.github.io/blog/2025/blog2/"><![CDATA[<p>I’m only into the second semester of my PhD, and I’m already having an existential crisis.</p> <p>To cope, I spent the little extra time I had over spring “break”<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" class="footnote" rel="footnote" role="doc-noteref">1</a></sup> going down a rabbit hole of PhD blogs and memoirs (starting with Philip Guo’s <a href="http://linyun.info/phd-grinding.pdf">The PhD Grind</a>, of course). It’s comforting to know that the emotions I’m experiencing aren’t rare. I now realize that the excitement I was experiencing for the first few months was, indeed, the honeymoon phase.</p> <p>When I arrived in Pittsburgh in August, graduate school seemed like a dream. Unlike any other educational experience I’ve had before, my core responsibility as a PhD student is to research. Professors joke that “if you’re getting Bs in your classes, you’re not spending enough time on research”. The purpose of taking courses is to gain skills and knowledge to apply to my research, so I have a lot of flexibility in terms of what and how I learn. As someone who always loved the discussion and dreaded the assignment, I really appreciate this aspect of grad school. There’s not much pressure to prove your aptitude via homework and exams. Instead, there’s an emphasis on brainstorming and thinking deeply—a prospect that is exciting but has made me the most sleep-deprived I have ever been.</p> <p>Don’t get me wrong. I still stand by what I wrote back in December. I am having fun in grad school. I guess recently I’ve just been doubting whether I’m actually cut out for it.</p> <p>With regard to my duties as a PhD student, for the past few months, I have spent my time:</p> <ul> <li>taking courses</li> <li>working on one of my advisor’s current projects</li> <li>reading a lot of papers</li> <li>coming up with half-baked, abstract ideas</li> <li>talking about aforementioned ideas with my advisor and other people</li> <li>revising ideas in response to new papers I find and feedback I receive</li> <li>getting lost in ideation</li> <li>recalibrating and going back to previous ideas</li> <li>getting frustrated</li> </ul> <p>Now, when I fill out my doctoral student review at the end of the semester, I’m probably just going to mention the first two bullet points. Because despite most of my time being spent on what is described in the remaining bullet points, none of that is noteworthy. However, that does not mean that I have not been productive or that I have been wasting my time. At least, that’s what I keep telling myself.</p> <p>When I started writing this piece, it seemed a little ridiculous at first to be having a “crisis” less than a year into my PhD. But I’ve found that several of my peers are in some sort of panic state/existentialist questioning mode right now. And it seems to stem from the expectation that we should be making more progress than we actually are.</p> <p>I recently mentioned to a senior PhD student in my program that I felt a little burnt out, to which they replied, “You’re a first year. How could you be burnt out?”. This response felt a bit harsh and invalidating, but I suppose as someone who has endured the challenges of being a PhD student for 6 years, it would be annoying to hear a first-year complain about their struggles.</p> <p>In reflection, I don’t think I’m actually burnt out. I think the reality of how difficult it is to produce good research is finally hitting me.</p> <p>So to get through this journey and avoid actual burnout (not just cognitive but also <a href="https://sauvik-das.medium.com/the-emotional-labor-of-your-ph-d-84e24846daff">emotional</a>), I’ve realized that I need to recalibrate my mindset. My current expectations for progress are unrealistic. I’m quick to compare myself to others. I’m impatient. I feel pressure to produce visible achievements. I’m focused too much on the finish line.</p> <p>To truly enjoy my PhD, I need to learn to bask in the process of learning and trying and failing and trying again. Because in research, there isn’t really a finish line. There’s always “future work” to do. I would like to attain a degree, but more than that, I want to become a good researcher. And a good researcher is more than awards and grants and publications. A good researcher is someone who asks insightful questions, who recognizes what gaps are worth addressing, and who is patient in refining work to a quality where it can be impactful. I’m sure there are other characteristics that I missed, but these are the few that came to mind.</p> <p>I’m definitely far from being a “good researcher”. The good news is I have lots of time. This is where I bring up the cliche, “it’s a marathon, not a sprint”. I repeat this to myself on the days when I wake up full of adrenaline and anxiety.</p> <p>Rather than fixate on what I’m outputting or not outputting, I want to shift to focus on who I would like to become, what skills I would like to refine, and what I would like to contribute to the field that I’m in. A good researcher embraces the process of learning, questioning, failing, and iterating. So for now, I’ll remind myself to be patient and to appreciate the small, incremental steps that shape me into who I hope to be.</p> <p>Cheers,</p> <p>Meryl</p> <div class="footnotes" role="doc-endnotes"> <ol> <li id="fn:1"> <p>Breaks are technically just for undergrads. But then why are grad classes and meetings also cancelled? <a href="#fnref:1" class="reversefootnote" role="doc-backlink">&#8617;</a></p> </li> </ol> </div>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="thoughts"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I’m only into the second semester of my PhD, and I’m already having an existential crisis.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Looking back on 2024</title><link href="https://merylye.github.io/blog/2024/blog1/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Looking back on 2024"/><published>2024-12-27T14:14:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-12-27T14:14:00+00:00</updated><id>https://merylye.github.io/blog/2024/blog1</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://merylye.github.io/blog/2024/blog1/"><![CDATA[<p>Leap years are always more eventful. There’s the Olympics and the presidential election, which are entertaining/exciting/nerve-wracking in their respective ways. Last leap year, in 2020, I graduated from high school and started college. Oh yeah, there was also a pandemic. Now, more than four years later, it’s the end of another momentous leap year.</p> <p>I graduated from college at the end of 2023, so 2024 was the start of another chapter for me. After celebrating western holidays in the states, my mom and I traveled to China in February for Lunar New Year. It had been five years since I last visited in China. COVID had discouraged us from traveling to see our extended family, but we finally decided that it was safe enough to go. I had never seen China in any season other than summer. It was cold and festive to say the least.</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blogs/blog1/lights-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blogs/blog1/lights-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blogs/blog1/lights-1400.webp 1400w," sizes="95vw" type="image/webp"/> <img src="/assets/img/blogs/blog1/lights.jpg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blogs/blog1/lantern.JPG-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blogs/blog1/lantern.JPG-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blogs/blog1/lantern.JPG-1400.webp 1400w," sizes="95vw" type="image/webp"/> <img src="/assets/img/blogs/blog1/lantern.JPG" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> Lights and lanterns are everywhere for lunar new year! </div> <p>Around this time, I was also hearing back from PhD programs to which I had applied back in December. Graduate school was an option that I was still unsure of, so I had only applied to a few select programs that I knew I would truly be willing to go to. Most were rejections–that put quite the dampener on my holiday spirit. Carnegie Mellon University ultimately offered me a spot in their Societal Computing PhD program, and I gratefully accepted. For any big life decision, I don’t think you’re ever 100% sure. But if God gives me an opportunity, I’m going to take it.</p> <p>After almost a month in China, we flew back home to the states. In late March, I traveled to Pittsburgh and attended the program’s open house, and was enamored of the community I met. I’ve never met a group of people with whom I’ve connected so well and so quickly. But it makes sense: not only did we get into the program via a selective process, we also all chose to pursue this niche field and career path. It’s no wonder our personalities and interests match incredibly well.</p> <p>For the remainder of my time at home—which although relaxing, I hope is the last time I will be idle for such an extended period—I explored various hobbies, read books, and fed my inner child. Taking this time to rest and recalibrate was important to me.</p> <div class="row mt-3 justify-content-center"> <div class="col-sm-8 col-md-6 mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blogs/blog1/NYC-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blogs/blog1/NYC-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blogs/blog1/NYC-1400.webp 1400w," sizes="95vw" type="image/webp"/> <img src="/assets/img/blogs/blog1/NYC.jpeg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption text-center"> NYC night skyline </div> <p>In July, I finally got a bit antsy and booked some last-minute trips. Even though I hadn’t submitted any work, I attended IC2S2 (International Conference on Computational Social Science) in Philadelphia, where I networked and met academics whom I had followed for a while as well as researchers whom I hadn’t been aware of. I also went to NYC for a few days, where I caught up with some friends and attended a Jimmy Fallon show taping. I got to see Scarlett Johansson, Joey King, and Channing Tatum in real life, so that was pretty cool. I brought back home a bag of Ess-a-Bagels, which sustained me for a week’s breakfasts.</p> <div class="row mt-3 justify-content-center"> <div class="col-sm-8 col-md-6 mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blogs/blog1/cmusign-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blogs/blog1/cmusign-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blogs/blog1/cmusign-1400.webp 1400w," sizes="95vw" type="image/webp"/> <img src="/assets/img/blogs/blog1/cmusign.jpeg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption text-center"> Me and the CMU sign. I love the contrasting colors in this picture. </div> <p>Then August finally rolled around, and I finally started my PhD. For all 2.5 years of my in-person college experience, I lived in campus dorms, so this is my first time renting an apartment. It’s not that much different, but it’s nice to have my own (albeit small) space. I’ve learned to develop a cleaning and meal prepping routine, as well as track my budget for each month. I’ve become close friends with the people in my cohort. I feel like I’ve found a place where I fit in. I haven’t felt this satisfied in a long time. I really hope that it lasts.</p> <p>These past five months have been the most sleep deprived I have ever been, but it’s also the most excited I have ever been. Nearly everything I do–classes, research, leisure–I do because I truly enjoy it; it contributes to who I want to become and am becoming.</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blogs/blog1/ghosts-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blogs/blog1/ghosts-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blogs/blog1/ghosts-1400.webp 1400w," sizes="95vw" type="image/webp"/> <img src="/assets/img/blogs/blog1/ghosts.jpeg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blogs/blog1/C88F006B-4A2D-4A6C-8187-B5FEBBC3E22A-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blogs/blog1/C88F006B-4A2D-4A6C-8187-B5FEBBC3E22A-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blogs/blog1/C88F006B-4A2D-4A6C-8187-B5FEBBC3E22A-1400.webp 1400w," sizes="95vw" type="image/webp"/> <img src="/assets/img/blogs/blog1/C88F006B-4A2D-4A6C-8187-B5FEBBC3E22A.jpeg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> I helped plan a few department pranks. </div> <p>For 2025, I hope to flesh out projects, take interesting classes, and pursue hobbies and friendships that fill my cup in work and life. I’m really happy with where I am right now–I write this to remind my frustrated future self of the enthusiasm that I had as a bright-eyed, bushy-tailed first year. Despite whatever difficulties I will inevitably face, I hope that I will see the value in all parts (good and bad) of the journey. Keep your head up! You got this!</p> <p>Cheers,</p> <p>Meryl</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="reflections"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Leap years are always more eventful. There’s the Olympics and the presidential election, which are entertaining/exciting/nerve-wracking in their respective ways. Last leap year, in 2020, I graduated from high school and started college. Oh yeah, there was also a pandemic. Now, more than four years later, it’s the end of another momentous leap year.]]></summary></entry></feed>